<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>nutsandpeace</title><link>https://example.com/</link><description>yo man! ideas</description><atom:link href="https://example.com/rss.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2018 &lt;a href="mailto:nutsandpeace@gmail.com"&gt;Vishnu Menon&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 18:02:10 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Regulating the new kid on the block</title><link>https://example.com/posts/regulating-the-new-kid-on-the-block/</link><dc:creator>Vishnu Menon</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regulating the new kid on the block.
Blockchain promises to be the next big thing, revolutionizing business and technology as we know it. It helps decentralize trust which in turn will reduce a lot of hiccups in industries such as healthcare, logistics and the global banking industry. The problem child of this technology seems to the birth of numerous cryptocurrencies born out of this cutting edge tech. Bitcoin - the poster boy of the crypto market has tumbled down after a historic rally, many associate the fall with the idea that it was a bubble and it had no intrinsic value, others argue that the futures contract by Wall Street on bitcoin have kept the prices on check.  The main concerns everywhere are based on evidence suggesting crypto currencies are being used for criminal activities such as drugs and weapons trade and financial crimes like money laundering and tax evasion. Leaders from around the world met at Davos for the World Economic Forum and hinted on tougher regulations to come into effect. British Prime Minister Theresa May, in her interview with Bloomberg stated that cryptocurrencies needs to be regulated due to its potential in aiding criminal activities around the globe. This only suggests that this will be tabled as an important agenda in the G20 summit which is soon to see the light of day in Argentina few months from now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China was the first to come down hard on the crypto market by forcing companies involved in crypto mining to shut down resulting in many companies relocating, rightfully so, as the Chinese want absolutely no uncertainty regarding their economy and its natural policy to monitor everything that can be monitored. China was the best place for miners due to the marginal cost of energy. This has resulted in companies moving to Russia to continue the trade. Russia according to popular public sources are considering a ban on the entire trade in the coming months. Meanwhile, India has introduced its first act of regulating the trade by letting the Income Tax department study the transactions of the popular exchanges and then by asking investors to pay taxes on capital gains if invested in the crypto market.  South Korea has made its move by making it mandatory for investors to trade in their real names and, will thus follow the KYC policies of banks. Japan too has followed by introducing broad checks on exchanges after the recent hack on one of its popular exchange which bore losses of over $500 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The economic problem behind cryptocurrencies have been debated across several forums and many traditional investors have outright said they want nothing to do with bitcoins and the crypto market. Problems with regulating cryptocurrencies primarily arises from the fact that there exists no single platform which brings together Blockchain experts, economists, bankers and policy makers. Vitalik Buterin, who developed Ethereum has tried to bring along many experts into the domain in recent times by publicizing the idea of crypto economics but the hostility towards crypto by governments keep prominent members from academia disinterested in the cause. Even though Smart Contracts exist from as early as 2006 the technology is very new and there is shortage of experienced programmers. There needs to be a huge contribution in this regard as financial technology needs to be blended with economics for it to be adapted among the masses. Many economists are wary of the idea since they suggest a limited number of bitcoins can never be used by people around the world not to mention the extreme volatility of these currencies. The fact that ultimately cryptos are being purchased using fiat currencies again confuses investors. Few experts also suggest that the surge in the prices was mainly due to the FOMO (Fear of Missing Out) among young investors. To base a value of a currency purely just on demand and supply also seems to be a nightmare to traditional investors. Another important issue policy makers and bankers point out is the completely unregulated process of  ICOs (Initial Coin Offering) as opposed to traditional methods. Tokens are offered from just about anyplace with an internet connection. Most of these ICOs eventually turn out to be scams. These problems make it the need of the hour for experts from different domains to come together to figure a coherent strategy to rationally implement a technology which can very well help change the lives of billions of people across the globe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://example.com/posts/regulating-the-new-kid-on-the-block/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 17:48:27 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>